hello everyone in this video we will
prove Pythagoras Theorem
visually in this Square we draw a
rectangle with one side a and the other
side is B with its diagonal as C now we
copy paste this over here so this these
all lengths are a and these all lengths
are B now from here this unshaded area
is equal to a square while this unshaded
area is equal to b square
we have to prove that this unshaded area
is equal to c² now let move the figure
like this one we move this triangle to
this region and this this unshaded
region is a square with its side length
C and thus this area is equal to C
Square by this figure we have a square +
B sare is = c² and that is the answer